你好，美丽的人们欢迎收看这个视频。
Hello The Beautiful People are welcome to this video.
我们将学习超级有用的排序命令，现在排序命令就是其中之一
We're going to be learning about the super useful sort command and now the sort command is one of those
命令，您可以在任何地方使用这些命令对数据进行排序，使其更有序、更易于管理。
commands that you can kind of use anywhere to sort data and make it more ordered and easier to manage.
在接下来的几个视频中，我将向您展示如何使用SORT命令对数据进行排序
And over the next few videos I'm going to be showing you how you can use the sort command to sort data
以各种不同的方式，还将向您展示一些用例，说明何时可以真正有用。
in a variety of different ways and also be showing you some use cases of when this can be really useful.
我们将建造一条超级强大的管道，允许我们以表格格式对数据进行排序。
And we'll be building a superpowerful pipeline that will allow us to sort data in tabular format.
所以到了最后，你将会非常擅长寻找数据，并真正了解如何
So by the end you're going to be amazing at sourcing data and really going into something of how to
使用SORT命令对Linux中的数据进行排序，无论数据位于何处，无论文本数字是否修改
use the sort command to sort data in Linux no matter where no matter whether it's text numbers modified
数字，甚至是表格中的数字。
numbers or even in tables.
哦哦。
Ooh.
所以这将是课程的一个非常有用的部分。
So this is going to be a very useful section of the course.
让我们直接跳进去吧。
Let's go ahead and jump right into it.
好的。
OK.
所以我应该说的第一件事是，我在我的桌面上放了三个文件，我有几个字没有
So the first thing I should probably say is that I've put three files on my desktop I've got words not
给我发短信，其中包含100个随机单词，没有特定的顺序排序，它们只是100个随机单词
text me which contains 100 random words sorted in no particular order they're just 100 random words
就在那个文件里。
that are just in that file.
我们有数字0到9.6T，这是一个文件，它有很多数字，但是没有数字，每个数字有100个数字
We've got the numbers 0 to 9.6 T which is a file that has loads of numbers and nothing 100 numbers each
在0到9之间。
between 0 and 9.
我们还有另外一个文件，叫做Numbers Top Tier XTi，我想这是另外100个随机的文件
And we've also got this other file here called Numbers top tier XTi which is I think another 100 random
数字，但它们不在特定的范围内，它们只是100个随机数，没有特定的
numbers but they do they're in no particular range and they're just 100 random numbers with no specific
对他们的限制。
limits on them.
我已经在参考资料部分提供了这些文件，以及有关如何
And I've made these files available in the resources section as well as some information about how I
创造了它们，所以你知道，如果你想抓住那些，你知道，尝试一下这些东西，然后你
created them so you know if you want to grab those you know try this stuff out for yourself then you
我知道你可以继续下载它们，然后试一试。
know you can go ahead and download them and give it a go.
好的。
OK.
那么让我们先来看看这些单词Datti Xti，它是一个随机包含100个单词的文件
So let's start off by taking a look at these words Datti XTi which is the file that contains 100 randomly
生成的单词。
generated words.
就像我说的，如果我们再打开一次，里面只有100个随机单词，没有什么特别的
And as I said like if we just open them up again it's just got 100 random words in there in no particular
不要特别订购100个随机生成的单词。
order no particular just 100 randomly generated words.
好的。
OK.
首先，我们如何对该文件进行排序，使其按字母顺序排序，以便开始的所有内容
So first of all how can we sort that file so that it's sorted alphabetically so everything that starts
带A的在顶部，如果以A开头，则Zed在底部。
with an A is at the top and if that starts with Zed is at the bottom.
这实际上是排序命令的默认行为，它是完全命名的命令，用于
Well that's actually the default behavior of the sort command which is the perfectly named command for
这类事情。
this kind of thing.
所以，如果我们只键入排序单词，而不是在这里，使用起来也非常简单。
So it's really simple to use as well if we just type sort words not here.
但是我们现在已经有了一个八年来排序的单词列表，所以您可以看到所有
But we've now got a list of sorted of sorted words from eight years and so you can see that all the
单词在顶部以或开头，所有以为什么开头的单词都在底部，而不是
words start with a or at the top and all the words that start with why are at the bottom and it doesn't
看起来我们有任何以Zed开头的东西，所以它们都是按字母顺序排序的，所以这是
look like we've got anything that starts with Zed So they've all been sorted alphabetically so that's
相当酷。
pretty cool.
当然，我们可以将标准输出写到文件中，或者您知道的，写到T命令中，我们可以使用它
And of course we can write the standard output to a file or you know to a T command and we can use that
也是。
as well.
好的，就像你知道的，我们可以说另一种说法，这里叫做有点傻乎乎的XTi，那就是
Ok so like you know we could say say another the here called sort of dotty XTi and that's going to be
把它放在那里，我们可以把它放到管道里，你知道，它只是写在标准上的
put there and we can pipe it down the pipeline that you know it's just written on standard all the same
规则适用。
rules apply.
所以，如果我们想要而不是解决问题又怎么样呢？
So what if we wanted instead of sorting it out.
如果我们想要反向排序呢？
What if we wanted to sort it in reverse.
我们该如何排序。
How would we sort.
所以泽德在顶端。
So Zed was at the top.
嗯，我想到两个选择。
Well two options come to mind.
首先，你可以做的就是像平常一样对单词进行分类。
First of all what you could do is you could just sort the words like just like normal.
然后将Python添加到TAC命令中。
But then Python into the TAC command.
就像你在这里看到的，发生了什么，这些字母以a开头，现在在
And as you can see here what's happened is the letters that there was a start with a are now at the
底部，以Close to Zed开头的单词现在位于顶部。
bottom and the words that start with close to Zed are now at the top.
原因是，我们知道，TAC命令会垂直翻转输出。
And the reason for that is that as we know the TAC command will sort of flip outputs vertically.
所以原本在底部的东西现在在顶部，在顶部的东西现在在底部。
So what would be at the bottom is now at the top and what was at the top is now at the bottom.
因此，这实际上就好像我们刚刚颠倒了正确的排序方式，但是更好的方法是
So that's effectively as though we've just reversed the sorting right but a better way to do it up I
假设一种更内置、更有效的方法是只给排序命令提供选项
suppose a more built in and efficient way to do it would be to just give the sort command the option
而这个选项代表的是反向。
and the option stands for reverse.
所以如果我这样做，我们可以再次看到，我们已经得到了这封信，看到了他，并抛出了这个词的开头
So if I do that we can see again we've got the letter saw him with a toss of the word starting with
A接近底部时，对不起，以Close to Zed开头的单词现在位于顶部。
a towards the bottom sorry and the words starting with close to Zed are now at the top.
现在你们可能注意到了，当我向你们展示这个输出时，我在货架上上下滚动
Now you may notice that when I'm showing you this output that I'm scrolling up and down the shelves
相当多。
quite a bit.
这就是最后一个命令的用武之地，我只需跳转到一个较少的命令来生成输出
So this is where the last command would come in I could just pop into a less command to make the output
更容易查看，因为现在我使用的是箭头键，而不是用鼠标垫滚动。
a bit easier to view because now I'm using the arrow keys instead of scrolling with my mouse pad.
所以你知道，这是一种更好的方式来处理媒体问答中的事情。
So that's you know a bit of a nicer way to deal with things in a press Q to come out of that.
所以它是建立在我们之前所做的基础上的。
So it's building upon what we did before.
非常棒的是，你知道你现在有了足够的积木，你可以解决同样的问题
So awesome know is how you have you now have enough building blocks that you can solve the same problem
以多种方式。
in multiple ways.
您知道，您现在可以使用该选项来反转它，或者如果您不想这样做的话。
You know that you could now use the option to reverse it or if you didn't want to do that.
你也可以用管道把它插到顶部。
You could also pipe it into the top.
赶快。
Come on.
这是Linux的一个伟大之处。
This is one great thing about Linux.
它给你提供了多种不同的方法来解决同一个问题，因为你有这么多不同的方法
It gives you multiple different ways to solve the same problem because you've got so many different
积木，所以在处理这些问题的方式上有很大的创造性空间
building blocks so there's plenty of room for creativity in the way that you approach these problems
因为没有一种正确的方法可以做到这一点。
as no necessarily one right way to do it.
现在我们来看看如何对数字进行排序。
So there we are now how about sorting numbers.
嗯，我这里有一个100个号码的清单，叫做Datti Eckstine号码。
Well I have a list here of 100 numbers called Numbers Datti Eckstine.
如果我们看一下，里面有100个数字，没有任何特定的大小限制。
If we take a look there's a 100 numbers in there that don't have any particular size limit.
它们可以是任何数字，但有100个。
They can be any number but there's 100 of them.
好的。
OK.
那么我们该如何对这些。
So how would we sort those.
用字母排序所以按字母顺序排序与按数字排序不同，按字母顺序排序与按数字排序是不同的
Well sorting with letters so sorting out is Ed sorting alphabetically is different from sorting numbers
它是按数字排序的。
which is sorting numerically.
所以，如果我们试着对数字进行排序，开始是这样的，你说它工作得不是很好，是哪一种？
So if we try to do sort numbers start s t like that you say it didn't really work that well what kind
这里发生的情况是，如果您注意到我们将此放入最后一个命令中，因此我们可以将其设置为
of happened here is if you if you notice that we put this into the last command so we can make it a
更容易看到所有的数字。
bit easier to see all the numbers.
从一开始就是这样。
It started with one.
我已经到了顶端，然后你看，现在我们得到了所有从2开始的数字，我们将
I've come to the top and then it kind of you see now we get in all the numbers that start with two we'll
选择以3开头的数字，以此类推。
get in on numbers that start with three and so on.
好的。
OK.
但是我们不是4，5，6，7，8，9，好的，你可以看到它是按第一个数字排序的，但是它是
But we're not four five six seven eight nine OK you can see it's sorting by the first digit but it's
而不是按该数字的值排序。
not sorting by the value of that number.
例如，160 16,029比1641大得多。
For example 160 sixteen thousand twenty nine is much bigger than 1641.
那么为什么它在它的正上方。
So why is it above it right.
没有真正意义上的数字大小。
There's no real sense of the size of the number.
事实是，它以数字1开头，并且在排序的过程中按数字排序，并且
It's just the fact that it starts with a number 1 and it's sorting numerically as it goes sorting and
当它只看数字的时候，它不是看数字的价值，而是只看数字的价值
as it goes along by just looking at the numbers it's not looking at the value of the numbers just looking
在数字上。
at the digits.
但是，如果您希望使用数字的值进行排序，则需要为排序命令提供an选项。
But if you want to sort using the value of the number you need to give the sort command the an option.
因此，该选项允许它按数字排序，或许可以看看这个。
So the option allows it to sort numerically maybe take a look at that.
现在你可以看到我们在顶部得到了最小的数字，所以我们从123开始。
Now you can see that we're getting the smallest numbers at the top so we're starting with 123.
然后，当他们下降的时候，数字会变得更大。
And then what the numbers are getting bigger as they go down.
所以要记住这一点很重要，只按数字排序与按数字排序是不同的
So that's something important to bear in mind sorting just by the digits is different than sorting by
整数的值。
the value of the whole number.
如果你想搜索整数的值，你需要给它一个选项。
And if you want to search the value of the whole number you need to give it an option.
当然，您可以反转这一点，这样最大的就会出现在顶部，方法是使用“给出选项”
And of course you can reverse this so that the biggest are at the top by using the giving the option
也可以倒车。
as well for reverse.
现在我们看到最大的数字在顶部，当我们向下滚动时，数字变得更小。
So now we see that the biggest numbers are at the top and as we scroll down the numbers get smaller.
所以这是非常非常好的。
So it's very very nice.
您已经看到了如何按字母顺序排序和文本，以及如何按数字排序，但是
So you've seen how to sort and text alphabetically and you've seen how to sort numbers numerically but
有一件事非常有用，那就是只显示独特的结果，而不是一遍又一遍地显示相同的结果
one thing that's very useful is to only show unique results rather than the same result over and over
一遍又一遍。
and over again.
我们这里有一个编号为0到1960的文件。
So we've got a file here called numbers 0 to 1960.
我的意思是，这是100行数据，但是只有行只包含从0到9的一个数字，所以您将
I mean that is 100 rows of data but only the rows only contain one of the numbers from 0 to 9 so you'll
一定要有一些复制品。
necessarily have some duplicates.
例如，我们这里有0，0，0。
For example here we've got 0 0 0.
好的。
OK.
这不仅仅是独一无二的结果，还有重复出现的结果。
It's not just unique results there are results that are repeated.
好的。
OK.
所以，如果我们看一下这里，我们试着对哪个是从0到9.6的锯号排序，它是用管道传输的
So if we take a look in here and we try to sort the which are the sort saw numbers 0 to 9.6 it is piped
最后一名。
into last.
你会看到所有的0都在前面，然后是所有的1，所有的2，3和4
You'll see that all the zeros come first then all the ones and all the twos and threes and fours the
五个六，七个八分之一和九个。
fives the six the seven eighths and the nines.
好的，那就有点烦人了。
OK and that's that's a bit annoying.
好的，也许我们只想要一次结果。
Ok maybe we just want to just have the results once.
好的，你要做的就是给排序选项排序卡曼迪你的选项，选项保持不变
Well to do the what you do is you give the sort option sort Kamandi you option and the option stands
代表独一无二的。
for unique.
当你不知道的时候，你会发现我们只有一次结果。
And when you do not know you'll see that we only get the results once.
好的。
OK.
所以让我来设置九到更少的。
So let me just set up nine to less.
这就对了。
There you go.
你可以说你只得到一次0到9的结果。
You can say you only get the results once 0 to 9.
这很有用，有时您不想让相同的结果一遍又一遍地重复。
This is useful sometimes you don't want to have the same result repeated over and over over again.
您只希望结果显示一次，此时您可以使用允许您
You only want the results to appear once and that's when you would use the you option which allows you
可以说是独一无二的。
to sort of uniquely.
当然，这仍然适用于其他选项，例如您知道我们现在正在排序的反转选项
And of course this still works with other options such as the reverse which you know now we're sorting
向后，您仍然可以按数字和您可能需要做的任何其他操作进行排序。
backwards and you can still sort numerically and whatever else you might need to do.
但这只是您可以确保每个结果只得到一次的方法。
But that's just how you can make sure that you only get each of the results once.
在这段视频中，您已经对SORT命令做了一些介绍，并且您已经看到您可以
So in this video you've had a bit of an introduction to the sort command and you've seen that you can
使用SORT命令对数据进行排序。
sort data using the sort command.
现在，该命令倾向于首先对最小的进行排序，因此在默认情况下，它倾向于从a到Zed或从0到9进行排序。
Now the command tends to sort smallest first so it'll tend to sort from a to Zed or from 0 to 9 by default.
好的，但是您可以使用选项来反转，这样就有了反转的选项。
Ok but you can reverse this by using the options so there are options for reverse.
如果您曾经对数字数据进行排序，并且希望排序考虑到实际的
And if you're ever sorting numerical data and you want the sort going to take into account the actual
值，而不仅仅是它包含的数字，然后确保给出排序
value of the number rather than just the digits that it contains then make sure that you give the sort
选项上，以允许它按数字排序。
on the an option to allow it to sort numerically.
如果您只想从排序命令中获得唯一的结果，请为它提供You选项，该选项
And if you only want to get unique results out of the sort command provide it with the you option which
过滤会不会只给出出现一次的结果。
will filter out just the results that appear once.
这就是我们在这段视频中介绍的内容。
So that's what we covered in this video.
但在下一个视频中，我们将更上一层楼，向您展示一些高级排序技术
But in the next video we're going to take it to a next level and show you some advanced sorting techniques
这将允许您对表格格式的数据进行排序。
that will allow you to sort data that comes in table format.
因此，我还将建造一条非常酷的管道，它也会做一些这样的事情。
So I'm also going to be building a really cool pipeline that will do some of this as well.
那么让我们继续，在下一个视频中直接开始，并将您的排序技巧带到下一个视频中
So let's just go ahead and get right into it in the next video and take your sorting skills to the next
标高。
level.